A Guide to the Papers of Archie G. Richardson 1918-1976
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- Photographs and Negatives
  - African American Schools in Virginia
    - Charlotte County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:46-47)
      - Keysville School
      - Emanlawin School 1934
      - Unknown 1933-1934
      - New Domestic Science Building-Charlotte County Training School
      - Mount Hanan School 1934
      - Whuler School 1934
      - Black Castle 1934
      - Faculty of Charlotte County Training School 1930-1931
      - 11th grade Charlotte County Training School 1930-1931
      - John Mitchell School-Charlotte County Training School 1934
      - Dupree School 1934
      - White Oak School 1934
      - Aspen Hill School 1934
      - Antioch School 1934
      - Charlotte County Court House (2)
      - Keysville (Private School)
      - Tuft E.H.Hall
      - Supt. of Halifax and Charlotte Counties
      - Supt. R.W. Babbitt 1934
      - Teachers Charlotte County 1933-1934
      - 11th grade Charlotte County 1934-1935
      - Supt. E.H. Hall
      - Facluty of Rev. Rax's Private School 1930-1931
    - Chesterfield 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:48)
      - 11th grade Chesterfield County Training School 1930-1931
      - Chesterfield County Teachers 1931-1932
      - Faculty-Chesterfield County Training School 1930-1931
      - Union Grove School 1935
      - Central School 1935
      - Union Branch School 1935
      - Drews Bluff 1935
      - Taylors School 1934
      - Winterpock School 1934
      - Blulah School 1934
      - Osborn School 1934
      - Chesterfield County Court House
      - Chesterfield County Training School Faculty 1930-1931
      - 11th grade Chesterfield County Training School 1931-1932
      - Senior Class Chesterfield County Training School 1934-1935
      - School Chorus-Chesterfield County Training School 1934-1935
    - Clarke County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:49)
      - School Band- Berryville School 1933-1934
      - Faculty and some Members of Graduating Class 1933-1934
      - Clarke County Court House
      - Louiseville School 1932
      - Groups at Louisville School
      - Supt., Doctor, and others at Louisville School 1933
    - Craig County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:50)
      - Craig County Court House 1932
      - Supt. McClenney 1932
    - Culpepper County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:51)
      - Mrs. Sadie Jones Mother of Norman at school 1931
      - Mitchell School (2) 1932-1933
      - Culpepper Schools 1934-1935
      - Thompson School Children 1930-1931
      - Charlie Thompson and wife (Epphransville) 1930-1931
      - Teachers-New School 1933
      - Bracktown School (bigger)
      - Madonna School
      - Jeffersonton School 1933
      - Muddy Run School 1932-1933
      - Perry School 1932-1933
      - 8th and 9th grades and Teachers 1934-1935
      - Bluehill School 1932-1933
      - Brandy School Building
      - Brandy School Upper Grades 1933-1934
      - Bastan School 1932-1933
      - Mrs. Kendrick
      - New Norman School 1933
      - Perry School
      - Odd Fellows Meeting-Norman School
      - Town School
      - Echungton School
      - Culpepper County Court House (2)
      - Primary School Groups-Culpepper Schools 1934-1935
      - Macedonia School
      - 8th and 9th grades-Culpepper Schools 1934-1935
      - Macedonia School Children 1932-1933
      - Supt. and Mr.s Kendrick
      - Supt. J.W. Kendrick
    - Cumberland County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:52)
      - Cumberland County Court House
      - Cumberland County School Board (3) 1933
      - Faculty-Cumberland County Training School 1931-1932
      - Faculty-Cumberland County Training School and Miss Carly 1932-1934
      - Girls Basketball Team- Cumberland County
      - Turkey Lick School 1934
      - Basketball Team-Cumberland County Training School 1931-1932
      - Faculty-Cumberland County Training School 1934-1935
      - Sugar Fork School 1934
      - 11th grade Cumberland County Training School 1933-1934
      - Flat Back School 1934
      - Bensous Springs School 1935
      - Supt. Bailey
      - H.S. Dept. 1931-1932
      - Senior Class- Cumberland County Training School 1932-1933
      - Lower Grades- Cumberland County Schools 1932-1933
      - Graham and SUpt. O.G. Bailey
    - Dinwiddie County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:53)
      - Cuter Store (4)
      - Dinwiddie County Training School- McKenney
      - Rocky Branch School
      - Dinwiddie (2) Oct 23
      - Dinwiddie County Court House
      - Center Star (4)
      - Supt. Scarborough
      - New Olive Branch School 1935
      - Dazler School
      - H.S. Dept. Dinwiddie County Training School 1931-1932
      - Prof. and Family 1931
      - Faculty of Dinwiddie County Training School 1930-1931
      - Graduating Class Dinwiddie
      - H.S. Dept. 10th grade 1934-1935
      - Dinwiddie County Training School Faculty 1931-1932
      - Old Olive Branch School 1932
      - Boys Quartet 1934
    - Elizabeth City County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:55)
      - Elizabeth City County Court House
      - Old Buckroe School
    - Essex County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 21:56)
      - 11th grade- John Mancene School 1933-1934
      - Tappahannock School 1934
      - 11th grade John Mancece School
      - John Mancene School
      - Faculty R.I. Academy 1930-1931
      - Faculty John Mancene School 1931-1936
      - Faculty of Essex County Training School 1934-1935
      - Tappahannock High School 1934-1935
      - Senior Class Professor Robinson-R.J. Academy 1931-1932
      - 11th grade R.I. Academy 1930-1931
      - Tappahannock School
      - Essex County Court House (2)
      - H.S. Group Essex County Training School 1934-1935
      - Supt. Essex and King and Queen Counties 1934
      - Essex County Training School 1934
      - White School 1934
      - R.I. Academy
    - Fairfax County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:1)
      - Side View of East Woodford School (3)
      - Band at Fairfax County Exhibit 1932
      - Miss Lillian Coney and Friends 1931
      - Fairfax County Court House
      - Baileys Cross Roads (3) 1932
      - Shelling Group Fairfax County Fair 1932
      - Fairfax County Court House (3)
      - Senior Class Manassas Inst. 1933-1934
      - Girls Phys. Ed. Class 1931-1932
      - Elk's Band
      - Parade at County Exhibit
      - Home of Supt. Hayden
      - Hayden Children (4)
      - Supt. M.D. Hall (2)
    - Fauquier County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:2)
      - Supt. and Daugter
      - Supt. J.C. Ambler (2)
      - Fauquier County Court House
      - Supt. and faculty of Fauquier Co. Training School 1930-1931
      - Senior Class Faquier Co. Training School 1934-1935
      - Faculty of Faquier Co. Training School (2)
      - Supt. of Faquier County
      - School Number 18 1935
    - Floyd County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:3)
      - Floyd County Court House
      - Groups of Teachers and Patrons 1933
      - Floyd County Training School
    - Fluvanna County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:4)
      - Oliver St.James School
      - Bus Driver -St. James School
      - Teachers and Supt. Abrames -St.James School
      - Columbia School 1935
      - Fluvanna County Court House Oct 6
      - New Fluvanna County Training School
      - Supt. Sneed and Trustee Loving
      - Supt. Shepperd
      - Granel Hill School 1935
      - Residence of Supt. 1935
      - Supt. J.P.Sneed
    - Franklin County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:5)
      - Snow Creek School
      - Ms. Sihuman School Children
      - Reverend and Mrs. Nelson 1931-1932
      - Smiths Chapel School (3) 1935
      - Teachers and Senior Class Franklin County Training School 1934-1935
      - Faculty Franklin County Training School 1931-1932
      - Ephesus School
      - Franklin County Training School 1931-1932
      - Rising Sun School
      - True Vine School
      - Bellevue School
      - 10th and 11th grade Franklin County Training School 1935-1936
      - Franklin Graded School
      - Ms. Lebanon School
      - Dillard Training School 1935
      - Supt. Ramsey (3)
      - Franklin County Court House
      - H.S. Group Franklin County Training School
      - Franklin County Teachers 1931-1932
    - Fredrick County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:6)
      - Fredrick County Court House
    - Giles County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:7)
      - Giles County Court House
    - Gloucester County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:8)
      - Gloucester County Court House
      - Gloucester County Training School- Home Econ Group
      - Graded Group (2) 1931-1932
      - 11th grade Gloucester County Training School 1931-1932
      - Faculty Gloucester County Training School 1933-1934
      - Phys Ed. Group Gloucester County Training School (2) 1931-1932
      - 11th grade Gloucester County Training School 1933-1934
    - Goochland County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:9)
      - 11th grade Faculty Goochland County Training School 1932-1933
      - Centerville School- Goochland County New School
      - Goochland County Training School Grades 10 and 11 1931
      - Patrons of Centerville School
      - Centerville School Children 1930-1931
      - Goochland County Training School 1934-1935
      - Emmans School 1934
      - Goochland County Training School Senior Class 1934-1935
      - Goochland County H.S. (New) 1934
      - Goochland County Court House (2)
      - Supt. of Gocchland County
      - Goochland County Training School H.S. Dept. 1933-1934
    - Grayson County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:10)
      - Home of a patron of the River Hill School
      - The River Hill School
      - Another View of Independence School with the United Methodist Church
      - Independence School 1935
      - Elk Creek School Children 1934-1935
      - Taylors Chapel School (2) 1935
      - River Hill School 1935
      - Old Town School (2) 1935
      - Elk Creek Senior Class 1934-1935
      - Some of the young people of Grayson County who are interested in playing baseball
      - The Independence School with the Baptist Church in the distant left of the picture
      - Grayson County Court House
    - Green County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:11)
      - Green County Court House
      - Standersville School Nov 10 1937
    - Greenville County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:12)
      - Greenville County Training School 11th grade 1934-1935
      - Greenville County Training School 8th grade 1931-1932
      - Greenville County Training School Faculty 1931-1932
      - Radium School
      - Orian School
      - Mt. Vernon School
      - Purdy School
      - Greenville County Court House
      - Miss Neal-Supervisor 1935
      - Supt. Halsinger
      - Dahlia School-Old Building
      - 11th grade Greenville County Training School 1933-1934
      - Claresville School 1935
    - Halifax County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:13)
      - Wesley Chapel 1935
      - Mountain Road School Number 2 1935
      - Andrew Farmer School 1935
      - Green Valley School 1935
      - Catawba School 1935
      - Mt. Laurel School 1935
      - Senior Class -Booker T. Washington H.S. 1934-1935
      - Halifax County Training School Senior Class 1934-1935
      - South Boston 7th grade 1930-1931
      - Halifax County Training School 11th grade 1933-1934
      - Halifax County Training School Faculty 1931
      - Training School Bus Dec 21 1937
      - Supervisor Mitchel and Teachers of Scottsburg School 1930
      - Haliax County Court House
      - Halifax County Training School 11th grade 1932-1933
      - Boys Phys Ed. Group 1931-1932
      - Scottsburg School Patrons 1930-1931
      - County Training School 11th grade 1931-1932
      - 11th grade County Training School 1930-1931
      - Piney Grove School 1935
      - Supt. of Halifax County
      - Scottsburg School 1935
      - Lennig School 1935
      - Ingram School 1935
      - Murphy's Grove School 1935
      - Scottsburg School
    - Hanover Boys School 1935 (Box-folder 22:14)
      - Boys Industrial School Exercises (2) 1935
      - Boys Industrial School June 7th 1935
      - School Building 1935
      - Hanover Boys Industrial School 1935
    - Hanover County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:15)
      - Hanover County Training School 11th grade 1934-1935
      - Beaver Damn School
      - Hanover County School Patrons
      - Hanover County Training School Faculty 1934-1935
      - Hanover County Training School Home Econ Class 1934-1935
      - Mountain Road School 1935
      - Hanover County Court House
      - New Union School
      - Rockville School
      - Doswell School
      - Supt. Hall
    - Henrico County 1929-1935 (Box-folder 22:16)
      - Virginia Randolph Faculty 1929-1930
      - Old Virginia Randolph Training School (2)
      - Virginia Randolph School Free Day 1931
      - Ridgeway School (white)
      - New Ridgeway White School
      - Millenium School with additions
      - Woodville School 1935
      - Supt. B.C. Goode (2)
      - Supt. A.C. Cooper
      - F.D.R. in Henrico 1934
      - Varina School
      - Quioccasin School
    - Henry County 1930-1936 (Box-folder 22:17)
      - Henry County Court House
    - Highland County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:18)
      - Flodd School Children 1932-1933
      - Manterey High School (White) 1933
      - Flood School 1933
      - Highland County Court House 1933
      - Mr. and MRs. Mauzy 1934
      - 11th grade Crabbottom School
      - Supt. Mauzy, J.B. Brick, and Prin. Phillips 1932-1933
    - Isle or Wright County 1930-195 (Box-folder 22:19)
      - Isle of Wright County Training School (2) 1932
      - Supt. Hall
      - Isle of Wright County Court House
    - James City County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:20)
      - James City County Teachers 1931-1932
      - James City County Training School 11th grade 1932-1933
      - Supt. Clarence Jennings and Sec. Mrs.A.L.Harris
      - Jamestown from the river (2)
      - James City County Court House
      - Williamsburg City Court House
    - King George COunty 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:21)
      - Edge Hill School 1933-1934
      - Sealston School 1935
      - Galcome School 1935
      - Prim School 1933-1934
      - Sealston School 1933-1934
      - Lambs Creek School (2) 1933-1934
      - Little Ark School 1935
      - Osso School 1933-1934
      - King George County Teachers 1933-1934
      - Edge Hill School (3) 1935
      - King George County Court House
      - Supt. Gayle's son (2) 1935
    - King William County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:22-23)
      - H.S. Group King William County Training School 1934-1935
      - H.S. Group King William County Training School 1934-1935
      - Beulahville School (4)
      - Officers Junior County League 1934
      - West Point School Senior Class 1934
      - Senior Class West Point School 1929
      - Teachers and Children-Blake School 1931-1932
      - King William County Teachers 1932-1933
      - Beulahville School
      - the 1st Emily Barrett Baby
      - Rucker Res. School
      - King William County Teachers 1932-1933
      - Mrs. Lunden, Fellow Teachers Beaulahville School 1931-1932
      - 7th grade Edgehill School 1934-1935
      - Venter School 1930-1931
      - Sweet Hall School 1933
      - Oak Grove School
      - H.S. Dept King William County Training School 1930-1931
      - Mancohick School
      - Churchview School
      - Canton Colored School 1933
      - Rumford School
      - Blake School
      - Central H.S. Senior Class 1934-1935
      - Indian School 1930-1931
      - Panwaki Indian School 1931-1932
      - Supt. J.B. Gayle
      - Supt. Walter Granher
      - King William County Court House
      - Infield School
    - King and Queen County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:24)
      - Bethlehem School (2) 1934
      - King and Queen County Training School Faculty 1933-1934
      - Faculty-King and Queen County Training School 1934-1935
      - Faculty-King and Queen County Training School 1931-1932
      - Senior Class-King and Queen County Training School 1931-1932
      - Agri Group-King and Queen County Training School 1930-1931
      - 11th grade King and Queen County Training School 1930-1931
      - King and Queen County Training School Faculty 1930-1931
      - 11 grade King and Queen County Training School Faculty 1932-1933
      - Agri Group- King and Queen County Training School 1931-1932
      - Line Pine School (2) 1934
      - King and Queen County Court House
      - Colored Teachers 1934-1935
      - Supt. and Mrs. Minor 1932
    - Lancaster County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:25)
      - Brownston School 1934
      - Lancaster County Training School- H.S. Dept 1930-1931
      - 11th grade Lancaster County Training School 1930-1931
      - Kambs Mill School (2) 1931-1932
      - Faculty Lancaster County Training School 1930-1931
      - 11th grade Lancaster County Training School 1931-1932
      - Kilmarnack School 1933
      - Kilmarnack School
      - Booker T. Washington School 1934-1935
      - New Lason School Children 1930-1931
      - 11th grade Lancaster County Training School 1933-1934
      - Senior Class Lancaster County Training School 1934-1935
      - Faculty-Lancaster County Training School 1931-1932
      - Lancaster County Teachers 1932-1933
      - Temple and Joy Dew 1933
      - Lancaster County Court House
      - Mrs. Hite School
      - Supt. Breuh and Mrs. Newman
    - Lee County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:26)
      - Bonnie Blue Gap School (2)
      - Pennington Gap Colored Training School 1932-1933
      - Bonnie Blue School Children 1932-1933
      - Lee County Court House
      - Supt. Shelbourne
    - Louisa County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:27)
      - Field Day (MT. Garland School) (3) May 1 1937
      - Louisa County Court House (2)
      - 10th and 11th grade Louisa County Training School 1934-1935
      - Five Folks 1932-1933
      - 8th and 9th grades Louisa County Training School 1930-1931
      - H.S. Dept Louisa County Training School 1932-1933
      - Ms. Garland School
      - H.S. Children (8th and 9th grade) Mrs. Garland School 1934-1935
      - Faculty Louisa County Training School Dec 1934
      - Faculty Louisa County Training School 1930-1931
      - Bels Cross Roads School
    - Loundon County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:28)
      - 8th and 9th grades Loundon County Training School 1930-1931
      - Faculty Loundon County Training School 1930-1931
      - Mountain
      - County White School Children 1931-1932
      - Hughesville School
    - Lunenburg County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:29)
      - Faculty of Lunenburg County Training School 1932-1933
      - Faculty of Lunenburg County Training School 1933-1934
      - 11th grade Lunenburg County Training School 1932-1933
      - Writesboro School 1935
      - Lunenburg County Training School Basketball Team 1934-1935
      - Camp School
      - Louie Humeson Hubert 1932
      - Senior Class Lunenburg Training School 1934-19335
      - Unity School 1935
      - Faculty Lunenburg County Training School 1932-1933
      - Bethany School 1935
      - Mt.Olive School 1935
      - Macedonia School 1935
      - Planetsville School 1935
      - Traffic School 1935
      - Friendship School 1935
      - Senior Class (11th grade) Lunenburg County Training School 1933-1934
      - Faculty Lunenburg County Training School 1932-1933
      - Lone Oak School 1935
      - High School Dept. 1931-1932
      - Pleasant Oak School 1935
      - Asbury School 1935
      - Daves School 1935
      - Grant Patrons Lunenburg County Training School 1932-1933
    - Madison County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:30)
      - Smith Ford School
      - Hoover School 1935
      - Avoda School 1934-1935
      - Williamsburg School(3)
      - Home Economics Cottage (Madison County School)(2) 1934-1935
      - Oak Grove School
      - Oak Park School Children 1930-1931
      - Oak Park School
      - Haywood School
      - Millstand School
      - Midway School Nov 10 1937
      - Brightwood School Nov 10 1937
    - Madison and Green County 1927-1935 (Box-folder 22:31)
      - Madison and Green Teachers
      - Madison and Green County Teachers 1927-1928
    - Matthews County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:32)
      - Matthews County Teachers 1933-1934
      - 10th grade Matthews County Training School 1933-1934
      - Matthews County Training School 1931-1932
      - Matthews County Teachers 1934-1935
      - Matthews County Training School Faculty 1931-1932
      - Matthews County Teachers 1933
    - Mecklenburg County 1927-1935 (Box-folder 22:33-40)
      - Lamberts Chapel School
      - Twins-Thyne Jack
      - Triplets at Thyne Jack April 1931
      - Whittles Grove School-Upper Grades 1931-1932
      - Lamberts Chapel School
      - School Children 1931-1932
      - Wrightman School
      - Dr. and Miss Wilson-Thyne Jack 1931
      - Blackridge School Dec 4th 1928
      - Lane School
      - Shaft at Mecklenburg County Training School 1927-1928
      - Old Blackridge School
      - County Freshman School
      - St. Marks Episcopal Church
      - 8th grade South Boston School 1930-1931
      - 9th grade South Boston School 1930-1931
    - Middlesex County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:41)
      - Union Grove School
      - Pine Grove School
      - 11th grade Middlesex County Training School 1931-1932
      - Shiloh School
      - Senior Class Middlesex County Training School 1934-1935
      - Middlesex County Teachers 1933-1934
      - Middlesex County Teachers 1933-1935
      - Middlesex County Court House
    - Montgomery County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:42)
      - Shawsville School
      - Ellistan School
      - Senior Class Christianburg Institute 1934-1935
      - Hill School 1935
      - Wake Forest School (3)
      - Blacksburg School 1935
      - Piney Woods School 1935
      - Radford School 1932-1933
      - Supt. C.C. Shelbourne 1934
      - Montgomery County Court House (2)
    - Nansemond County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:43)
      - Supt. Williams
      - Nansemond Collegiate Institute
      - Nansemond County Court House
      - Faculty Nansemond Collegiate Institute 1930-1931
      - 11th grade Nansemond County Training School 1931-1932
      - Huntersville School (2)
      - H.S. Group Nansemond County Training School 1930-1931
    - Nelson County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:44)
      - Nelson County Court House
      - Ryan School Children 1938
    - New Kent County 1927-1935 (Box-folder 22:45)
      - New Kent County Teachers 1931-1932
      - Faculty New Kent County Training School 1934-1935
      - Faculty NEw Kent County Training School 1933-1934
      - Plum Paint School
      - Tunstalls School
      - New Kent County Training School 1933-1934
      - 11th grade New Kent County Training School
      - 2nd Liberty School
      - Children and Patrons and Mount Castle School 1931-1932
      - Cumberland School
      - 11th grade New Kent County Training School 1934-1935
      - St. Peters School
      - H.S. Children and Teachers (2nd Liberty School) 1931-1932
      - Cooks Mills School 1927
      - Rear View Mt.Nebo-Rosenwald School
      - Old Peters Church (4)
      - New Kent County Court House
      - Cooks Mill School (2)
      - Mrs. S.A. Antchfrier-Supervisor Sept 22
      - Lanexa School
      - Children at Lanexa School
      - Quinton School (3) 1929
    - Norfolk County 1930-1935 (Box-folder 22:46)
      - Norfolk County Portsmouth
      - Supt. Hurst
      - 11th grade Norfolk County Training School 1931-1932
      - Faculty of County Training School 1931
      - Pupils of 9th and 9th grades-South Norfolk School 1931-1932
      - 12th grade Boys-South Hill School 1931-1932
      - Faculty of Norfolk County Training School 1931-1932
      - 6th and 7th grade pupils-Churchland School 1931-1932
      - 11th grade pupils Norfolk County Training School 1930-1931
      - Senior Class Norfolk County Training School 1933-1934
      - Churchland School (30's)
      - 11th grade Norfolk County Training School 1934-1935
      - 11th grade Norfolk COunty Training School 1932-1933